Christopher Snyder

Self-taught developer looking for the next big challenge. http://snyderc.me | http://github.com/snyderc | hello@snyderc.me

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Redux, Git, MongoDB, Firebase, Jest, Enzyme, HTML, CSS. Familiar with Python.

SELECTED PROJECTS

Vote Remote — Tech Lead (July 2018 - present)

http://www.voteremote.us/

Led technical development of first version of product, launched Sept 2018. Worked with product design team and project leads to define project requirements and translate into technical tasks for self and 2 other developers. Volunteer project for nonprofit. ReactJS, Firebase, HTML, CSS.

Coast to Coast — Personal Project (Summer 2018)

http://coast-to-coast.snyderc.me/

Remake of the Apple IIe game "How The West Was 1 + 3 X 4," which teaches mathematical order of operations to elementary school students. Outlined and recreated game workflow, coded own PEMDAS parser. JavaScript.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Accion Systems Inc., Boston, MA — Operations Manager

August 2015 - March 2018

Project managed two office/lab moves and construction buildouts for growing startup, moving from 500SF to 2,500SF to 10,000SF. Worked directly with CEO to design and implement company procedures.

Disciplined Entrepreneurship, Cambridge, MA — *Editor*

Disciplined Entrepreneurship Workbook Sept 2016 - April 2017 | Disciplined Entrepreneurship July 2012 - July 2013 Hired by MIT instructor to edit two books on startup product development. Both books published by Wiley.

MIT: Martin Trust Center for MIT Entrepreneurship, Cambridge, MA — Program Coordinator

Program Coordinator October 2011 - July 2015 | Communications Assistant April 2011 - October 2011

Ran event logistics for Demo Day event with 1000+ attendees. Created database to automate expense reporting.

EDUCATION

Tufts University, Medford, MA — Bachelor's Degree

2007 - 2011

Summa cum laude in political science. Phi Beta Kappa. 3.81 GPA.

Programming coursework:

Intro to Computer Science (C++), Data Structures (C++), Intro to Game Development (Java)